<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Tile Biome Editor</name>
  <author>James Malone</author>
  <packageId>jamalone.tilebiomeeditor</packageId>
  <url>https://github.com/james-malone/boringbiome</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <description>Select any tile on the world map and change its biome and features.

When you pick a landing site you're stuck with whatever biome the planet generated there. Tile Biome Editor adds buttons to the selected tile so you can set it to anything you like — turn a scorching desert into a temperate forest, a bog into tundra, or make a spot windy, foggy, fertile or mineral-rich.

[HOW TO USE]
- Select a tile on the world map. The buttons appear both on the "select landing site" screen and the in-game world map.
- "Change biome..." — choose a biome from the list; the tile is repainted to match.
- "Change features..." — toggle tile features (mutators) such as windy, foggy, sunny, wet climate, fertile, mineral-rich, more/less wildlife, and so on. Active features are marked "(active)"; click one to toggle it.

[WHAT IT CHANGES]
The tile's biome and a curated, safe set of feature mutators (weather, wildlife and resource/ground modifiers). Landforms (peninsulas, islands, coasts), rivers, roads, and tile names are left intact — so you can re-biome a desert peninsula into a windy forest and it stays a peninsula. Structural/landmark mutators (caves, lakes, ancient ruins) are intentionally not offered, since they are built for map generation.

Tile features require the Odyssey DLC; without it the "Change features..." menu is simply empty and the biome editor works on its own.

[IMPORTANT — TIMING]
The biome drives map generation, so change a tile BEFORE its map is generated. Editing a tile only affects maps generated afterward; it does not rewrite a map that already exists.

[COMPATIBILITY]
- RimWorld 1.6 (Odyssey).
- Requires Harmony (load it above this mod).
- Safe to add to an existing save, and safe to remove: it only adds a UI button and stores no data of its own.

Source and issues: https://github.com/james-malone/boringbiome</description>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
  </loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>
